<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ideatrash</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ideatrash.net/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ideatrash.net</link>
	<description>Writing, publishing, geekdom, and errata. By Steven Saus.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 20:31:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/cropped-DARK_Square-1-1.jpg?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>ideatrash</title>
	<link>https://ideatrash.net</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144741783</site>	<item>
		<title>Game Rating Fail &#8211; EA Says Inappropriate Ads Aren&#8217;t Their Problem</title>
		<link>https://ideatrash.net/2020/01/game-rating-fail-ea-says-inappropriate-ads-arent-their-problem.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=game-rating-fail-ea-says-inappropriate-ads-arent-their-problem</link>
				<comments>https://ideatrash.net/2020/01/game-rating-fail-ea-says-inappropriate-ads-arent-their-problem.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=game-rating-fail-ea-says-inappropriate-ads-arent-their-problem#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 16:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[<span class='p-author h-card'>steven</span>]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ideatrash.net/?p=103592</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Wherein Electronic Arts says it's not their problem their E10 game is showing mature and offensive advertisements.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://ideatrash.net/2020/01/game-rating-fail-ea-says-inappropriate-ads-arent-their-problem.html?pk_campaign=feed&pk_kwd=game-rating-fail-ea-says-inappropriate-ads-arent-their-problem"><img width="300" height="200" src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ben-white-qDY9ahp0Mto-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="Game Rating Fail &#8211; EA Says Inappropriate Ads Aren&#8217;t Their Problem" align="center" style="display: block;margin: 0 auto 20px;max-width:100%;" /></a><div class="e-content">
<p>You would not expect to sit your family down in a theater to watch <em>Frozen II</em>… only to see the red band trailer for the R-rated remake of <em>The Grudge</em> to play in its gory detail before the movie.  And if it <em>did</em> happen, you’d be pissed at the theater which showed that advertisement to an inappropriate audience.</p>



<p>Apparently, Electronic Arts disagrees.</p>



<p>As imperfect as ratings are – and believe me, I <em>know</em> how imperfect they are – they’re still useful.  It’s nice to know <em>roughly</em> what you’re getting into.  As the ESRB (the rating group for video games) puts it:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Use the ESRB video gameratings guide to understand how the rating system works and how to use it to select appropriate video games and apps for your family</p><cite>https://www.esrb.org/ratings-guide/</cite></blockquote>



<p>And as Wikipedia notes, these aren’t just self-regulatory things:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Despite being self-regulatory, in Canada, games rated by the ESRB are required by law to be rated and/or restricted, though this only varies at a province and territory level. </p><cite>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Video_game_content_rating_system#North_America</cite></blockquote>



<p>It’s easy to see how online interactions can violate the ratings a game can have; for example, the latest release of Minecraft now features a now-familiar warning when you connect to an online server: </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2020-01-24-1579872290_1357x390_scrot.jpg?fit=1024%2C294&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-103593" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure><p>Again, this kind of notice is <em>important</em>, because lots of kids play games relatively (or completely) unsupervised.</p>



<p>Which brings us to Electronic Arts and a game franchise I’ve been playing on various platforms for a decade: <em>Plants vs. Zombies</em>.  Specifically, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entertainment_Software_Rating_Board#Ratings" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">E10+ rated</a> mobile version of <em>Plants vs. Zombies 2</em>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2020-01-24-1579879135_709x237_scrot-560x187.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-103594" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure><p>As you can see, this game “Contains Ads” – usually voluntarily shown to get a perk in the game.  I was a bit surprised to see the below ad pop up a <em>lot</em> for a while this week:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Screenshot_2020_01_20_13_31_16.jpg?fit=1024%2C485&amp;ssl=1" alt='Image with a partially clad woman pushing her chest out and saying her cloth[sic] is too tight, and offering two options for the "Commander" - to take it off or adjust it.' class="wp-image-103595" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure><p>Which led to me contacting both the publisher of the game <em>Kiss of War</em> (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entertainment_Software_Rating_Board#Ratings" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">rated M</a>) and Electronic Arts [1]:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>I have seen the attached advert displayed for the game <em>Kiss of War</em> whilst playing <em>Plants vs. Zombies 2</em>.<br><br>This advert seems to suggest that <em>KoW</em> endorses and encourages sexual harassment in the military. As a veteran who knows a number of fellow soldiers who have suffered sexual harassment at the hands of their officers and NCOs, this strikes me as particularly offensive.<br><br>I recognize that <em>KoW</em> is a M17+ rated game, and that game may (and apparently does) contain offensive elements<br><br>However – and more important to EA – this inappropriate advert is appearing in an E10+ rated game. I have a hard time believing that endorsing sexual harassment falls under the E10+ rating.<br><br>Please respond posthaste with what steps, if any, your respective companies are taking to rectify this situation. </p></blockquote>



<p>Let’s be honest. With the world on fire (probably literally again), this probably shouldn’t be our <em>biggest</em> priority.  </p>



<p>But it’s still <em>a</em> priority.</p>



<p>I know female soldiers and vets who have been harassed and assaulted <em>by superiors</em> while  on active duty. I know a lot more women who have been harassed and  assaulted in civilian life.  So to say I’m <em>not thrilled</em> is an understatement.</p>



<p>I’ve yet to hear back from Chengdu Nibirutech Inc (or “tap4fun”) who make <em>Kiss of War</em>; but I did hear back from Electronic Arts – both via a direct e-mail inquiry and via the “Contact Us” form on the website.  Their responses were… <em>unhelpful</em>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2020-01-24-1579871978_696x484_scrot-560x389.jpg" alt="Hello,

Thank you for contacting EA Mobile.
 
Please visit https://help.ea.com/ ; You should be able to find answers to many of your questions within our Knowledge Base or FAQ sections.
 
If you are unable to find the answer you're looking for, click 'Talk To A Game Advisor' so that we may help you with your specific issue.
 
Thanks again for your interest in EA Mobile, and we hope you continue to enjoy playing our games on your mobile devices!


Sincerely,

EA Mobile Customer Service" class="wp-image-103596" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"><figcaption>“Look at our website, which doesn’t address the issue.”</figcaption></figure><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2020-01-24-1579872033_659x1067_scrot.jpg?fit=632%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" alt=" 	Thank you for contacting EA help. My name is Shravan and I'll be helping you with your issue today regarding Plants vs. Zombies 2.

I see you're concerned regarding advert of game &quot;kiss of war while playing plants vs zoombies 2&quot; which is encouraging the sexual harassment in the military. I agree that must be disappointing for you. I'll try my best to help you out with the best possible solutions.

I wold like to inform you that the game &quot;kiss of war&quot; doesn't belongs to us. So, we're unable to control harassment content in the game. I would advise you to contact them to stop this.

I also would like to inform you that the game Plants vs. Zombies 2 is a free game available to download on play store. So, the adverts are managed by Google. If you don't want to see the adverts, please contact Google and ask for further help.

Denying a request for a customer support representative is never easy as our one and only aim is to fix the issue player have.

Our honest intention is to help our customers with the best of solutions, however, at times, we are bound or held back by the unavailability of the options on our end. I hope that you understand game limitation here.

I apologize for not being able to live up to your expectations and appreciate your kind understanding in this regard

Should you have any further questions regarding this or any other issues, please do not hesitate to let us know. You can also find answers to common questions on our Help Center at http://help.ea.com, or ask our community experts by visiting Answer HQ at http://answers.ea.com.

Thank you again for contacting EA help" class="wp-image-103597" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"><figcaption>I’m pretty sure this is a chatbot in e-mail form.</figcaption></figure><p>The (probable) chatbot tries to sidestep the issue by saying it’s all Google’s responsibility because it’s on the Play store.  Except that isn’t the case:  Google Play explicitly says the ads “are placed by the app developer”, and that the Play store doesn’t mark what kind of content is in the ads.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery columns-2 is-cropped"><ul class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://i0.wp.com/ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Screenshot_2020_01_21_17_26_15.jpg?fit=485%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-id="103598" data-full-url="https://i0.wp.com/ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Screenshot_2020_01_21_17_26_15.jpg?fit=568%2C1200&amp;ssl=1" data-link="https://ideatrash.net/?attachment_id=103598" class="wp-image-103598" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://i1.wp.com/ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Screenshot_2020_01_21_17_26_25.jpg?fit=485%2C1024&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-id="103599" data-full-url="https://i1.wp.com/ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Screenshot_2020_01_21_17_26_25.jpg?fit=568%2C1200&amp;ssl=1" data-link="https://ideatrash.net/?attachment_id=103599" class="wp-image-103599" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure></li></ul></figure><p>What if the chatbot just mis-spoke, and the ads (placed by the developer, Electronic Arts) are being served by Google’s advertising network? Even then, it’s pretty much EA’s responsibility as well:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>You can set the maximum ad content rating for a specific app or for your entire account within the AdMob user interface.</p><cite>https://support.google.com/admob/answer/7562142?hl=en</cite></blockquote>



<p>So EA says it’s Google’s fault. Google says it’s EA’s fault.  And the Chinese company who makes the game isn’t responding.</p>



<p>Even if I was to be <em>amazingly</em> charitable and think that this was a mis-rated advert that got through – something that I’ve seen happen with bloggers before – there is <em>no</em> indication that EA would report the advert, block the advert, or take <em>any</em> action whatsoever.</p>



<p>Can the advert exist?  Absolutely. Although I find it offensive, I’m not suggesting the advertisement be erased from existence.</p>



<p>I’m saying that it shouldn’t be showing in a game that I (supposedly) should be okay with letting a ten year old play by themselves.  The fact that <em>this</em> ad showed up makes me wonder what <em>other</em> ads Electronic Arts (a $22.9 BILLION dollar company) would show a ten year old so they could make a <em><strong>few more pennies</strong></em>.</p>



<p>Doing something – <em>anything</em> – about an inappropriate advertisement that shows <em>in your game</em> that is marked as appropriate for a fifth grader is the <em>only</em> acceptable reaction.  </p>



<p>Not a high bar to clear.</p>



<p>So I sent one more reply to EA just before publishing this post.  It reads as follows:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>The prior response from EA was factually incorrect – ads are placed by the app developer, per Google Play’s own website, and even if EA uses AdMob for advertising, there are rating restrictions and ways to report mis-rated adverts.  <br><br>It is extremely disappointing that EA claims that it is unable to do anything about inappropriate content being delivered via an ad network that EA chooses.  <br><br>It leads me to wonder what else EA would show ten year olds in order to make a few pennies.  <br><br>I have written this experience up and am publishing it.  </p></blockquote>



<p>If you wish to contact EA yourself and ask them what else they think is okay to show your kids, you can mail them at <a href="mailto:customerexperience@ea.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">customerexperience@ea.com</a> or <a href="mailto:help@eamobile.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">help@eamobile.com</a>, or on Twitter at <a href="https://twitter.com/plantsvszombies" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">@PlantsvsZombies</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/EAHelp" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">@EAHelp</a>.</p>



<p>[1] I have learned from hard experience that trying to get a human at Google is damn near impossible.</p>



<p>Featured Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@benwhitephotography?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Ben White</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/shock-family?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Unsplash</a></p>
</div><img src="https://stevensaus.com/matomo/piwik.php?idsite=2&amp;rec=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2F2020%2F01%2Fgame-rating-fail-ea-says-inappropriate-ads-arent-their-problem.html%3Fpk_campaign%3Dfeed%26pk_kwd%3Dgame-rating-fail-ea-says-inappropriate-ads-arent-their-problem&amp;action_name=%3Cspan+class%3D%27p-name%27%3EGame+Rating+Fail+%26%238211%3B+EA+Says+Inappropriate+Ads+Aren%26%238217%3Bt+Their+Problem%3C%2Fspan%3E&amp;urlref=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2Ffeed" width="0" alt="" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;">]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://ideatrash.net/2020/01/game-rating-fail-ea-says-inappropriate-ads-arent-their-problem.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=game-rating-fail-ea-says-inappropriate-ads-arent-their-problem/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<enclosure url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ben-white-qDY9ahp0Mto-unsplash.jpg" length="39997" type="image/jpeg"/><media:content url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ben-white-qDY9ahp0Mto-unsplash.jpg" width="1200" height="801" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">103592</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Dark Reality &#8211; A Dayton Band You Don&#8217;t Want To Miss</title>
		<link>https://ideatrash.net/2020/01/my-dark-reality-a-dayton-band-you-dont-want-to-miss.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=my-dark-reality-a-dayton-band-you-dont-want-to-miss</link>
				<comments>https://ideatrash.net/2020/01/my-dark-reality-a-dayton-band-you-dont-want-to-miss.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=my-dark-reality-a-dayton-band-you-dont-want-to-miss#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[<span class='p-author h-card'>steven</span>]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rock]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ideatrash.net/?p=103575</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I got to see this insanely talented rock band live; you should check them out!]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://ideatrash.net/2020/01/my-dark-reality-a-dayton-band-you-dont-want-to-miss.html?pk_campaign=feed&pk_kwd=my-dark-reality-a-dayton-band-you-dont-want-to-miss"><img width="300" height="200" src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/75513610_151053786296616_2236884302799306752_n-300x200.jpg" alt="My Dark Reality &#8211; A Dayton Band You Don&#8217;t Want To Miss" align="center" style="display: block;margin: 0 auto 20px;max-width:100%;" /></a><div class="e-content">
<p>Last week I saw that BandsInTown listed a venue really near me that I’d not heard of before – <a href="https://www.turnbucklesandbrews.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Turnbuckles and Brews</a>.  And the band it was telling me about was <a href="https://www.facebook.com/mydarkrealityband/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">My Dark Reality</a>.  The cover charge was pretty minimal, so off we went.</p>



<p>The other bands were okay – talented local-ish bands, often with some catchy tunes, but none of them really had a “wow” moment for us.  That is, until <a href="https://www.facebook.com/mydarkrealityband/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">My Dark Reality</a> took the stage.  </p>



<p>We were blown away.  The musicianship was great, the energy was electric, and after the first song, I realized I needed to take some video.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/2020-01-23-1579823112_1171x433_scrot.jpg?fit=1024%2C379&amp;ssl=1" alt="The band, from their Facebook page" class="wp-image-103583" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure><p>While the audio in the videos is a bit blown out at times (I wasn’t far from the speakers), you can still hear enough to see the utterly <em>amazing</em> work by this band.  The influences of goth, punk, and blues rock all come together in a most satisfying way.</p>



<p>If my poor-quality audio isn’t enough, you can also check out their first single, “Ashes to Ashes” (the third video) on streaming and digital sale platforms (links below).</p>



<p>And I <em>strongly</em> encourage you to pick up any other music they put out, as well as <em>insisting</em> that you attend any of their live shows that you’re able to.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/phuzvbGBlm4?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;"></iframe>
</div></figure><figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BdDE0chfI4Y?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;"></iframe>
</div></figure><figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GnUJHu1IPag?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;"></iframe>
</div></figure><p>Uploaded with the consent of the band.  Check out their single “Ashes to Ashes” available all over the place:</p>



<p>Spotify:  <a href="https://spoti.fi/2TYgf46" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://spoti.fi/2TYgf46</a><br> Apple Music: <a href="https://apple.co/2TYggVI" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://apple.co/2TYggVI</a><br> Amazon: <a href="https://amzn.to/2tzGa7L" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://amzn.to/2tzGa7L</a><br> Google: <a href="http://bit.ly/2NTVXVD" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">http://bit.ly/2NTVXVD</a><br> CD Baby: <a href="http://bit.ly/2RjE9p4" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">http://bit.ly/2RjE9p4</a><br> Youtube: <a href="https://youtu.be/Aav-PAqvVu0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://youtu.be/Aav-PAqvVu0</a></p>
</div><img src="https://stevensaus.com/matomo/piwik.php?idsite=2&amp;rec=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2F2020%2F01%2Fmy-dark-reality-a-dayton-band-you-dont-want-to-miss.html%3Fpk_campaign%3Dfeed%26pk_kwd%3Dmy-dark-reality-a-dayton-band-you-dont-want-to-miss&amp;action_name=%3Cspan+class%3D%27p-name%27%3EMy+Dark+Reality+%26%238211%3B+A+Dayton+Band+You+Don%26%238217%3Bt+Want+To+Miss%3C%2Fspan%3E&amp;urlref=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2Ffeed" width="0" alt="" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;">]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://ideatrash.net/2020/01/my-dark-reality-a-dayton-band-you-dont-want-to-miss.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=my-dark-reality-a-dayton-band-you-dont-want-to-miss/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<enclosure url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/75513610_151053786296616_2236884302799306752_n.jpg" length="205230" type="image/jpeg"/><media:content url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/75513610_151053786296616_2236884302799306752_n.jpg" width="960" height="640" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">103575</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upgrading Voxelmap and Keeping Your Waypoints in #Minecraft</title>
		<link>https://ideatrash.net/2019/12/upgrading-voxelmap-and-keeping-your-waypoints-in-minecraft.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=upgrading-voxelmap-and-keeping-your-waypoints-in-minecraft</link>
				<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 16:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[<span class='p-author h-card'>steven</span>]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howto]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ideatrash.net/?p=103551</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[How to keep your waypoints while upgrading VoxelMap to 1.15 in Minecraft!]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://ideatrash.net/2019/12/upgrading-voxelmap-and-keeping-your-waypoints-in-minecraft.html?pk_campaign=feed&pk_kwd=upgrading-voxelmap-and-keeping-your-waypoints-in-minecraft"><img width="300" height="169" src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/minecraft-3609241_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="Upgrading Voxelmap and Keeping Your Waypoints in #Minecraft" align="center" style="display: block;margin: 0 auto 20px;max-width:100%;" /></a><div class="e-content">
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-thumbnail is-resized"><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/minimap.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-103552" width="244" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"><figcaption>VoxelMap in action</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>I love minimaps in Minecraft.  I get lost without a GPS in real life; it’s even worse in games.  Especially <em>big</em> ones like Minecraft.  So I’ve been using minimaps with waypoints since I first learned about them. </p>



<p>The one I use now is <a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/voxelmap" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">VoxelMap</a>, which is hands-down the <em>best</em> minimap for Fabric modloader, and I was thrilled to see that it’s updated for 1.15.1.  But <a href="http://myminecraft.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">on the server I play on</a>, I have a <em>bunch</em> of waypoints that I didn’t want to lose.  So here’s how to upgrade!</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-medium"><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/2019-12-21-1576946056_658x666_scrot-560x552.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-103553" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure></div>



<p>First, make sure you have a backup from 1.14 that has your waypoints in it.  Go into your 1.14 Minecraft mods folder and copy /.minecraft/mods/mamiyaotaru somewhere safe.</p>



<p> Then install the VoxelMap mod like you would normally.  (After I write this, it’ll also be in my <a href="https://senorwombat.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">MultiMC and Technic modpacks</a>, so upgrade normally there.)  Log in to the server of your choice (or local world).  </p>



<p>You’ll see the VoxelMap intro screen.   Don’t worry about configuring it yet; <em>we’re also giong to copy your old preferences over</em>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/2019-12-21-1576945398_2390x1280_scrot-560x261.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-103554" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure><p>Press “M” and then when prompted, tell VoxelMap that it’s a multiworld server.  (Overworld, Nether, and The End are each a separate world, so the answer is probably yes.)  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/2019-12-21-1576945452_834x405_scrot-560x272.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-103555" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure><p>Click “New Name” and give it <em>the same name that you did before</em>.  In my case, that’s “main”.  Press enter to save it.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://i2.wp.com/ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/2019-12-21-1576945480_2390x1280_scrot.jpg?fit=1024%2C631&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-103556" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure><p>Also create a waypoint – just anywhere, it doesn’t matter.  Repeat this with the Nether and End if you have waypoints in those locations. </p>



<p>Leave the server and <strong><em>CLOSE MINECRAFT</em></strong>.  If you do not close the program completely, <em>this does not work</em>.</p>



<p>You will notice that in your 1.15 installation (or modpack installation) there’s a new  /.minecraft/mods/mamiyaotaru folder.  Copy the <strong><em>OLD</em></strong><em> </em>mamiyaotaru folder from 1.14 into the 1.15 directory.  </p>



<p>Replace the new files with the old ones.  </p>



<p>Restart Minecraft; your waypoints should have returned.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/2019-12-21-1576945896_870x610_scrot-560x393.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-103557" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure><p>I’m not sure why doing it this way is necessary, but just copying it over beforehand didn’t work for me; YMMV.</p>



<p>And if you’re able, <a href="https://www.patreon.com/MamiyaOtaru" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">support the author of this mod on Patreon</a>, and maybe I’ll see you on <a href="https://myminecraft.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">MyMinecraft</a>!</p>
</div><img src="https://stevensaus.com/matomo/piwik.php?idsite=2&amp;rec=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2F2019%2F12%2Fupgrading-voxelmap-and-keeping-your-waypoints-in-minecraft.html%3Fpk_campaign%3Dfeed%26pk_kwd%3Dupgrading-voxelmap-and-keeping-your-waypoints-in-minecraft&amp;action_name=%3Cspan+class%3D%27p-name%27%3EUpgrading+Voxelmap+and+Keeping+Your+Waypoints+in+%23Minecraft%3C%2Fspan%3E&amp;urlref=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2Ffeed" width="0" alt="" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;">]]></content:encoded>
									<enclosure url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/minecraft-3609241_1920.jpg" length="105527" type="image/jpeg"/><media:content url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/minecraft-3609241_1920.jpg" width="1200" height="675" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">103551</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Featured Texture Pack: Have A &#8220;Smartwatch&#8221; In Minecraft With Mi Mined</title>
		<link>https://ideatrash.net/2019/12/featured-texture-pack-have-a-smartwatch-in-minecraft-with-mi-mined.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=featured-texture-pack-have-a-smartwatch-in-minecraft-with-mi-mined</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[<span class='p-author h-card'>steven</span>]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texture pack]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ideatrash.net/?p=103524</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Let your Minecraft clock give you even more information with this texture pack!]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://ideatrash.net/2019/12/featured-texture-pack-have-a-smartwatch-in-minecraft-with-mi-mined.html?pk_campaign=feed&pk_kwd=featured-texture-pack-have-a-smartwatch-in-minecraft-with-mi-mined"><img width="300" height="169" src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/desktop-wallpaper-landscape-minecraft-682766-300x169.jpg" alt="Featured Texture Pack: Have A &#8220;Smartwatch&#8221; In Minecraft With Mi Mined" align="center" style="display: block;margin: 0 auto 20px;max-width:100%;" /></a><div class="e-content">
<p><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/mi-mined" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Mi Mined</a> is a pretty simple – and <em>clever</em> – texture pack to help make the clock even more useful in Minecraft (versions 1.13 through 1.15 as of writing this).  </p>



<p>It’s an addon texture pack that just changes the clock face so that it gives you even more information.  It works in the hotbar <em>and</em> when mounted in an item frame:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery columns-2 is-cropped"><ul class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/2019-12-18_18.35.53.jpg" alt="" data-id="103526" data-link="https://ideatrash.net/?attachment_id=103526" class="wp-image-103526" width="434" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/2019-12-18_18.35.39-1.jpg" alt="" data-id="103527" data-link="https://ideatrash.net/?attachment_id=103527" class="wp-image-103527" width="90" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure></li></ul></figure><ul><li>Shows when players can sleep.</li><li>When light level reaches it’s maximum in surface or when it decreases.</li><li>When villagers sleep/socialise/start working.</li><li>When hostile mobs start spawning or burning.</li></ul><figure class="wp-block-gallery columns-3 is-cropped"><ul class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clock_12.png" alt="" data-id="103530" data-link="https://ideatrash.net/?attachment_id=103530" class="wp-image-103530" width="32" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clock_24.png" alt="" data-id="103532" data-link="https://ideatrash.net/?attachment_id=103532" class="wp-image-103532" width="32" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clock_26.png" alt="" data-id="103533" data-link="https://ideatrash.net/?attachment_id=103533" class="wp-image-103533" width="32" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clock_29.png" alt="" data-id="103534" data-link="https://ideatrash.net/?attachment_id=103534" class="wp-image-103534" width="32" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clock_71.png" alt="" data-id="103537" data-link="https://ideatrash.net/?attachment_id=103537" class="wp-image-103537" width="32" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clock_80.png" alt="" data-id="103539" data-link="https://ideatrash.net/?attachment_id=103539" class="wp-image-103539" width="32" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure></li></ul></figure><p>It definitely adds something to the entire clock experience!  Check this texture pack out at:</p>



<p><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/mi-mined" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/mi-mined</a></p>



<p>Featured  Photo by <strong> <a href="https://www.pexels.com/@evenecer-andujar-207487?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=pexels" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"> Evenecer Andujar </a> </strong> from <strong> <a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/desktop-wallpaper-landscape-minecraft-682766/?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=pexels" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"> Pexels </a> </strong></p>
</div><img src="https://stevensaus.com/matomo/piwik.php?idsite=2&amp;rec=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2F2019%2F12%2Ffeatured-texture-pack-have-a-smartwatch-in-minecraft-with-mi-mined.html%3Fpk_campaign%3Dfeed%26pk_kwd%3Dfeatured-texture-pack-have-a-smartwatch-in-minecraft-with-mi-mined&amp;action_name=%3Cspan+class%3D%27p-name%27%3EFeatured+Texture+Pack%3A+Have+A+%26%238220%3BSmartwatch%26%238221%3B+In+Minecraft+With+Mi+Mined%3C%2Fspan%3E&amp;urlref=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2Ffeed" width="0" alt="" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;">]]></content:encoded>
									<enclosure url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/desktop-wallpaper-landscape-minecraft-682766.jpg" length="66974" type="image/jpeg"/><media:content url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/desktop-wallpaper-landscape-minecraft-682766.jpg" width="1200" height="675" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">103524</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Automatically Shape Bandwidth On Linux</title>
		<link>https://ideatrash.net/2019/12/automatically-shape-bandwidth-on-linux.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=automatically-shape-bandwidth-on-linux</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 18:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[<span class='p-author h-card'>steven</span>]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[command line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traffic shaping]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ideatrash.net/?p=103508</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Automatic traffic shaping for when you change networks frequently (like with a laptop).]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://ideatrash.net/2019/12/automatically-shape-bandwidth-on-linux.html?pk_campaign=feed&pk_kwd=automatically-shape-bandwidth-on-linux"><img width="300" height="196" src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/carbon-300x196.png" alt="Automatically Shape Bandwidth On Linux" align="center" style="display: block;margin: 0 auto 20px;max-width:100%;" /></a><div class="e-content">
<p>I’ve written about <a href="https://ideatrash.net/2014/07/making-wondershaper-play-nice-on-lan.html">wondershaper</a> before (though ignore the tweaks I mention there – <a href="https://github.com/magnific0/wondershaper" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">wondershaper <em>is</em> updated and is available at GitHub</a>) ; it’s a handy little tool that will keep any one application from hogging all the available bandwidth from your computer.  While it doesn’t create miracles on its own, combining it with Quality of Service (QoS) rules on your router can make everything run a bit more smoothly.</p>



<p>To use a metaphor, QoS on your router is like a traffic cop between a highway onramp (the internet) and the surface streets (your LAN), waving high-priority traffic through more quickly than low-priority traffic.  Wondershaper is a <em>different</em> traffic cop doing the same job, but only handling traffic in a neighborhood (your computer) going onto the main surface streets (your LAN).  Having one helps, having both can help make things run a <em>lot</em> more smoothly.  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/LAN-560x439.jpg" alt="Graph demonstrating where QoS and wondershaper work." class="wp-image-103512" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure><p><a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/75660/the-beginners-guide-to-qos-on-your-router/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Setting up QoS rules is a little tricksy</a> (and beyond the scope of this post), but is worth it.  <a href="https://github.com/magnific0/wondershaper" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Wondershaper</a> is a lot simpler, since it’s cleverly written and is just handling traffic from a single computer.  But what if your computer is a laptop (like mine) and different places you work from have different bandwidth amounts?  That’s where  my <code>automatic_wondershaper_wombat</code> script comes in.</p>



<p>The “normal” installation results in the script being called every time you connect or disconnect from a network.  When you connect, it waits until your computer isn’t under high load, then uses <code>speedtest-cli </code>to determine the available bandwidth <em>to that computer</em> from the router.  It then automatically determines and sets the bandwidth limits, all behind the scenes.  When you disconnect from the network, it clears all the settings it put in place.   Optionally, you can run it manually to have it re-examine and re-apply its limits.</p>



<p>It logs to <code>syslog</code> as well as creating a simple text file at <code>/tmp/bandwidthqueues</code> listing the interface used, the downspeed limit, and the upspeed limit.</p>



<p>You can check it out on <a href="https://github.com/uriel1998/automatic_wondershaper_wombat" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">GitHub</a>, <a href="https://gitlab.com/uriel1998/automatic_wondershaper_wombat" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">GitLab</a>, or <a href="https://git.faithcollapsing.com/automatic_wondershaper_wombat/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">my private git repository</a>, which includes detailed step-by-step installation instructions, tested on Debian Buster.</p>
</div><img src="https://stevensaus.com/matomo/piwik.php?idsite=2&amp;rec=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2F2019%2F12%2Fautomatically-shape-bandwidth-on-linux.html%3Fpk_campaign%3Dfeed%26pk_kwd%3Dautomatically-shape-bandwidth-on-linux&amp;action_name=%3Cspan+class%3D%27p-name%27%3EAutomatically+Shape+Bandwidth+On+Linux%3C%2Fspan%3E&amp;urlref=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2Ffeed" width="0" alt="" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;">]]></content:encoded>
									<enclosure url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/carbon.png" length="85349" type="image/png"/><media:content url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/carbon.png" width="1008" height="657" medium="image" type="image/png"/><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">103508</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grunkle Steven&#8217;s Bees (for Minecraft 1.15)</title>
		<link>https://ideatrash.net/2019/12/grunkle-stevens-bees-for-minecraft-1-15.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=grunkle-stevens-bees-for-minecraft-1-15</link>
				<pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 15:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[<span class='p-author h-card'>steven</span>]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multimc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ideatrash.net/?p=103497</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[This week saw the release of version 1.15 of Minecraft, and that means it's time for a new modpack!  Introducing Grunkle Steven's Bees!  ]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://ideatrash.net/2019/12/grunkle-stevens-bees-for-minecraft-1-15.html?pk_campaign=feed&pk_kwd=grunkle-stevens-bees-for-minecraft-1-15"><img width="300" height="200" src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GrunkleStevensBees-300x200.jpg" alt="Grunkle Steven&#8217;s Bees (for Minecraft 1.15)" align="center" style="display: block;margin: 0 auto 20px;max-width:100%;" /></a><div class="e-content">
<p>This week saw the release of version 1.15 of Minecraft, and that means it’s time for a new modpack!  Introducing Grunkle Steven’s Bees!  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://senorwombat.com/images/GrunkleStevensBees.jpg" alt="" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"></figure><p>I’ve not only created a <a href="https://www.technicpack.net/modpack/grunkle-stevens-bees.1583107" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Technic modpack</a>, but I’ve also been playing around with MultiMC, so you can import the modpack as a <a href="https://multimc.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">MultiMC</a> instance (or download the zip) from here:  <a href="https://git.faithcollapsing.com/GSBees/blob/master/GSBees.zip" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://git.faithcollapsing.com/GSBees/blob/master/GSBees.zip</a></p>



<p>I’ll be updating both versions simultaneously, so for example, when Optifine/Optifabric are updated, it will be added to both versions at the same time.  You can find the full list of my modpacks at the <a href="https://senorwombat.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Senor Wombat page</a>.  The full list of tweaks, mods, etc <em>as of this time of writing</em> is below!</p>



<p>And as always, join us online at <a href="http://myminecraft.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">MyMinecraft</a>!  (server: play.myminecraft.com)</p>



<h1>Mods</h1>



<h2>Gameplay</h2>



<p><strong>Amecs: Alt-Meta-Escape-Control-Shift</strong><br>
Amecs is a mod that tries to improve your keyboard immersion. Therefore 
it introduces several modifier keys (alt, control and shift) for now to 
give you a larger variety to chose from when making keybindings.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/amecs" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/amecs</a> </p>



<p><strong>ChatPing</strong><br>
A mod that makes a sound when phrases are said in chat.<br><a href="https://github.com/professorg/ChatPing" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://github.com/professorg/ChatPing </a> </p>



<p><strong>Command Macros</strong><br>
Have a command you commonly use? Tired of repeatedly typing it in over 
and over? Wouldn’t it be easier to press a key on your keyboard to run 
the command?<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/command-macros" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/command-macros</a> </p>



<p><strong>EasierChests</strong><br>
A Mod to easier move stuff between inventory and chests<br><a href="https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/easierchests?gameCategorySlug=mc-mods&amp;amp;projectID=279501" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/easierchests?gameCategorySlug=mc-mods&amp;projectID=279501</a> </p>



<p><strong>EasierVillagerTrading</strong><br>
This is a mod for people who trade with villagers a lot. It does not add
 any functioniality to villagers, and it doesn’t allow you to do 
anything you can’t do in vanilla Minecraft, but it allows you to do the 
same things with a lot less clicks and mouse movements.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/easiervillagertrading" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/easiervillagertrading</a> </p>



<p><strong>Enchanted ToolTips</strong><br>
Display information about the enchant in an item’s ToolTip. Works for 
any enchanted item, including Books. Enchanted ToolTips is highly 
customizable, you can modify everything to what information is display 
in the tooltip, to adjusting the descriptions of the enchant.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/enchanted-tooltips" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/enchanted-tooltips </a> </p>



<p><strong>Grid</strong><br>
This mod displays a grid-like overlay over the world, with configurable 
spacing, so the blocks you’re interested in get highlighted 
automatically.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/grid" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/grid </a> </p>



<p><strong>Light Overlay</strong><br>
A simple mod to provide users with NEI-like light overlay.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/light-overlay" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/light-overlay</a> </p>



<p><strong>Tooltip Autowrap</strong><br>
Does what it says on the tin.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/tooltip-autowrap" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/tooltip-autowrap</a> </p>



<h2>Aesthetic</h2>



<p><strong>Mambience</strong><br>
MAmbience adds a large amount of dynamic ambient sounds.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/mambience" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/mambience</a> </p>



<p><strong>Presence Footsteps</strong><br>
Expect to see a more rich and immersive Minecraft world, one where Presence<br>
Footsteps adds new and more dynamic sounds for every block the player walks on.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/presence-footsteps" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/presence-footsteps</a> </p>



<p><strong>Runorama</strong><br>
runorama allows you to replace your title screen menu’s background with the panoramic screenshots you take in game!<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/runorama" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/runorama</a> </p>



<p><strong>Smoke Extender</strong><br>
This is a simple clientside mod that does a simple thing: Change the 
default behaviour of campfire emitted smoke to last longer. It only 
changes the one made with a hay bale, not the default one.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/smoke-extender/files/2840979" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/smoke-extender/files/2840979</a> </p>



<h2>Utility</h2>



<p><strong>Fabric API</strong><br>
Core API library for the Fabric toolchain<br><a href="https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/fabric?gameCategorySlug=mc-mods&amp;amp;projectID=306612subscribe" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/fabric?gameCategorySlug=mc-mods&amp;projectID=306612subscribe</a> </p>



<p><strong>Fat Experience Orbs</strong><br>
This mod makes it so that nearby experience orbs merge together<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/fat-experience-orbs" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/fat-experience-orbs</a> </p>



<p><strong>Mod Menu (Fabric)</strong><br>
Adds a mod menu to view the list of mods you have installed.<br><a href="https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/modmenu?gameCategorySlug=mc-mods&amp;amp;projectID=308702" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/modmenu?gameCategorySlug=mc-mods&amp;projectID=308702</a> </p>



<h1>Data Packs:</h1>



<p><strong>Disable Hostile Grief</strong><br>
This data pack was created to allow Villagers to harvest crops, and Snow
 Golems to place snow layers, while also retaining the desirable 
features of gamerule mobGriefing = false. Note that this data pack sets 
the mobGriefing gamerule to true.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/customization/disable-hostile-grief-data-pack" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/customization/disable-hostile-grief-data-pack</a> </p>



<h1>Texture Packs Modifying Theme:</h1>



<p><strong>Jerm’s Better Leaves Add-on</strong><br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/better-leaves-add-on-2-0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/better-leaves-add-on-2-0</a><br>
This pack retextures the leaves to look a little more realistic, and adds a custom model to them to look a little more bushy. </p>



<p><strong>Open Lower Grass</strong><br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/open-lower-grass" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/open-lower-grass</a> </p>



<p><strong>HD Font – Roboto</strong><br>
The Material font, now on Minecraft – 1.13 and up.<br><a href="https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/hd-font-roboto?gameCategorySlug=texture-packs&amp;amp;projectID=298082" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/hd-font-roboto?gameCategorySlug=texture-packs&amp;projectID=298082</a> </p>



<p><strong>Round Trees</strong><br>
Do you want Round Trees in Minecraft without a mod? Well, I created a pack that brings these cool ROUND TREES!<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/round-trees-mc-vanilla-1-8-1-13" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/round-trees-mc-vanilla-1-8-1-13</a> </p>



<p><strong>Dark GUI theme</strong><br>
Updated by me, based on https://www.planetminecraft.com/texture_pack/dark-theme-4253588/ </p>



<p><strong>Glass Doors</strong><br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/glass-doors" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/glass-doors </a> </p>



<p><strong>Jappa 1.14 Glass with Connected Textures! [16x]</strong><br>
Clean Glass! Remove those line streaks from Default Glass, Stained Glass, and Ice!<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/new-glass" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/new-glass</a> </p>



<h1>Recommended But Not Included Due To License:</h1>



<p><strong>New Default +</strong><br>
New Default+ stays faithful to the default textures while also improving
 them with more optimized, detailed, and refined textures.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/newdefaultplus" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/newdefaultplus </a> </p>



<p><strong>Pixel Reality – Luminance</strong><br>
Realistic lighting with vanilla textures or any other pack, a perfect 
alternative to shaders if your machine just can’t handle them!
<a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/pixel-reality-luminance" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/pixel-reality-luminance</a> </p>



<p><strong>Pixel Reality – Atmosphere</strong><br>
Add a realistic sky to vanilla Minecraft or any pack! Needs Optifine.<br><a href="https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/pixel-reality-atmosphere?gameCategorySlug=texture-packs&amp;amp;projectID=227812" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/pixel-reality-atmosphere?gameCategorySlug=texture-packs&amp;projectID=227812</a> </p>



<h1>Waiting for updates/conflicts</h1>



<p>The following crashed my game every time or haven’t updated; I’m waiting for new versions. </p>



<p><strong>VoxelMap</strong><br>
Minimap and Worldmap. Have an overview of your surroundings, or view the entire world. Create waypoints.<br><a href="https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/voxelmap?gameCategorySlug=mc-mods&amp;amp;projectID=225179" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/voxelmap?gameCategorySlug=mc-mods&amp;projectID=225179</a> </p>



<p><strong>Dynamic FPS</strong><br>
Dynamic FPS automatically reduces the speed at which minecraft renders when<br>
it’s not focused (to 1 FPS) or hidden (no renders at all).<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/dynamic-fps" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/dynamic-fps</a> </p>



<p><strong>Enchanted Tooltip</strong><br>
Display information about the enchant in an item’s ToolTip. Works for any enchanted item, including Books.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/enchanted-tooltips" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/enchanted-tooltips</a> </p>



<p><strong>FoamFix for Minecraft</strong><br>
Simple, targeted optimizations for 1.8+ Minecraft<br><a href="https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/foamfix-for-minecraft?gameCategorySlug=mc-mods&amp;amp;projectID=278494" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/foamfix-for-minecraft?gameCategorySlug=mc-mods&amp;projectID=278494</a> </p>



<p><strong>Optifine</strong><br><a href="https://www.optifine.net/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.optifine.net/</a> </p>



<p><strong>Optifabric</strong><br>
A mod that can be used to run Optifine on the Fabric Mod Loader. It does
 this by taking the official optifine mod and making it compatible with 
the Fabric Mod Loader at runtime.<br><a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/optifabric/files/2744943" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/optifabric/files/2744943</a></p>
</div><img src="https://stevensaus.com/matomo/piwik.php?idsite=2&amp;rec=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2F2019%2F12%2Fgrunkle-stevens-bees-for-minecraft-1-15.html%3Fpk_campaign%3Dfeed%26pk_kwd%3Dgrunkle-stevens-bees-for-minecraft-1-15&amp;action_name=%3Cspan+class%3D%27p-name%27%3EGrunkle+Steven%26%238217%3Bs+Bees+%28for+Minecraft+1.15%29%3C%2Fspan%3E&amp;urlref=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2Ffeed" width="0" alt="" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;">]]></content:encoded>
									<enclosure url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GrunkleStevensBees.jpg" length="232086" type="image/jpeg"/><media:content url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GrunkleStevensBees.jpg" width="900" height="600" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">103497</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proxies, TT-RSS, and Newsboat (Or Newsbeuter), Oh My</title>
		<link>https://ideatrash.net/2019/12/proxies-tt-rss-and-newsboat-or-newsbeuter-oh-my.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=proxies-tt-rss-and-newsboat-or-newsbeuter-oh-my</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 19:49:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[<span class='p-author h-card'>steven</span>]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ideatrash.net/?p=103485</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[If Newsboat and Newsbeuter don't authenticate with a nginx proxy to Apache, this post is for you. ]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://ideatrash.net/2019/12/proxies-tt-rss-and-newsboat-or-newsbeuter-oh-my.html?pk_campaign=feed&pk_kwd=proxies-tt-rss-and-newsboat-or-newsbeuter-oh-my"><img width="300" height="200" src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/markus-spiske-qjnAnF0jIGk-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="Proxies, TT-RSS, and Newsboat (Or Newsbeuter), Oh My" align="center" style="display: block;margin: 0 auto 20px;max-width:100%;" /></a><div class="e-content">
<p>Offered here as a solve for anyone else who finds this problem (everyone else will probably not understand this, and that’s okay):</p>



<p>I had a functioning installation of TT-RSS being served by Apache, then decided to put a nginx proxy in front of my home websites/servers.  Immediately after doing so, I could no longer authenticate with <a href="http://www.newsbeuter.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Newsbeuter</a> or <a href="https://newsboat.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Newsboat</a> (a fork of Newsbeuter that is actively maintained).</p>



<p>My nginx setup has all HTTP traffic redirected to HTTPS, as you should, and then it communicated with Apache via HTTP on a different port.  And in my Newsboat config, I had this line:</p>



<p>ttrss-url “https://my.tt-rss.install.com”</p>



<p>After messing around with Apache and nginx configurations, I finally stumbled upon the right solution: changing that line in my Newsboat configuration to:</p>



<p>ttrss-url “http://my.tt-rss.install.com”</p>



<p>And now it works just fine.</p>



<p>I’m not sure <em>why</em> changing it to http instead of https made a difference, but it did. So hopefully this helps someone else down the line.  </p>



<p>Now I might just update <a href="https://ideatrash.net/2013/03/scripts-and-utilities-to-make.html">my scripts for Newsbeuter</a> to be more functional with my current flow. </p>
</div><img src="https://stevensaus.com/matomo/piwik.php?idsite=2&amp;rec=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2F2019%2F12%2Fproxies-tt-rss-and-newsboat-or-newsbeuter-oh-my.html%3Fpk_campaign%3Dfeed%26pk_kwd%3Dproxies-tt-rss-and-newsboat-or-newsbeuter-oh-my&amp;action_name=%3Cspan+class%3D%27p-name%27%3EProxies%2C+TT-RSS%2C+and+Newsboat+%28Or+Newsbeuter%29%2C+Oh+My%3C%2Fspan%3E&amp;urlref=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2Ffeed" width="0" alt="" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;">]]></content:encoded>
									<enclosure url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/markus-spiske-qjnAnF0jIGk-unsplash.jpg" length="125463" type="image/jpeg"/><media:content url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/markus-spiske-qjnAnF0jIGk-unsplash.jpg" width="1200" height="800" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">103485</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inequality In The Work Week</title>
		<link>https://ideatrash.net/2019/11/103467.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=103467</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 22:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[<span class='p-author h-card'>steven</span>]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[sociology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[structural discrimination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inequality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[systemic inequality]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ideatrash.net/?p=103467</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The work week was a great progressive triumph. It's also an example of structural inequality.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://ideatrash.net/2019/11/103467.html?pk_campaign=feed&pk_kwd=103467"><img width="300" height="200" src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/johann-walter-bantz-woE5G6zzFQo-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="Inequality In The Work Week" align="center" style="display: block;margin: 0 auto 20px;max-width:100%;" /></a><div class="e-content">
<p>Sometimes it’s difficult to see inequality. Particularly when it’s the structural kind.  (Previously discussed in <a href="https://ideatrash.net/2015/08/you-might-be-acting-like-bigot-and.html">You might be acting like a bigot – and never mean to</a>, <a href="https://ideatrash.net/2017/08/the-cowardly-way-to-address-racism-and.html">The Cowardly Way To Address Racism (and other bigotry)</a>, and <a href="https://ideatrash.net/2009/11/structures-of-power-vignette-six.html">Structures of Power (Vignette Six)</a>. </p>



<p>There’s another example that really brings home how we can be surrounded by a pervasive structural system and rarely actually <em>think</em> about it.</p>



<p>It’s the classism of the work week.</p>



<p>Don’t get me wrong – I’m <em>fantastically</em> thankful for the progressives and unions that changed working conditions in the United States and <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/where-did-40-hour-workweek-come-n192276" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">got us the 40-hour work week</a>.  At the same time, it still solidified and institutionalized structural discrimination based on class.</p>



<p>This is most evident with things like appointments and activities around children. [1]  It’s still difficult to get doctor appointments outside of “normal business hours”.  For many people, they still have to use vacation or sick time to see a doctor (even for a checkup or preventative care). Even more have to weigh the benefits of going to see a physician against simply <em>not getting paid</em> for that time. PTO/PTA activities are even worse, largely because it also inherits the sexism from before women started becoming part of the workforce. </p>



<p>And so we end up with a system where those who are upper class, where a single income is (somehow) enough to support the family, are more and better able to take care of themselves and participate in society.</p>



<p>It’s important to emphasize that this isn’t <em>on purpose</em>. This isn’t an <em>intended</em> effect – it’s just an outcome from the way the system is set up.  Once you stop and examine it, once you stop and <em>see</em> the structural inequality in our daily life, it’s obvious. </p>



<p>But until then, you’re a fish who doesn’t think of water as being wet.</p>



<p>And that’s the way structural inequality works. </p>



<p>Featured Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@1walter2?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Johann Walter Bantz</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/parent-teacher-organization?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Unsplash</a></p>
</div><img src="https://stevensaus.com/matomo/piwik.php?idsite=2&amp;rec=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2F2019%2F11%2F103467.html%3Fpk_campaign%3Dfeed%26pk_kwd%3D103467&amp;action_name=%3Cspan+class%3D%27p-name%27%3EInequality+In+The+Work+Week%3C%2Fspan%3E&amp;urlref=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2Ffeed" width="0" alt="" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;">]]></content:encoded>
									<enclosure url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/johann-walter-bantz-woE5G6zzFQo-unsplash.jpg" length="66905" type="image/jpeg"/><media:content url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/johann-walter-bantz-woE5G6zzFQo-unsplash.jpg" width="1200" height="799" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">103467</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>So You&#8217;re Anti-Glasses?: Dismantling Right Wing Arguments</title>
		<link>https://ideatrash.net/2019/11/so-youre-anti-glasses-dismantling-right-wing-arguments.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=so-youre-anti-glasses-dismantling-right-wing-arguments</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 22:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[<span class='p-author h-card'>steven</span>]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inequality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[systemic inequality]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ideatrash.net/?p=103458</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Trying to close the empathy gap, one example at a time.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://ideatrash.net/2019/11/so-youre-anti-glasses-dismantling-right-wing-arguments.html?pk_campaign=feed&pk_kwd=so-youre-anti-glasses-dismantling-right-wing-arguments"><img width="300" height="200" src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ugo-4EDJgGj419U-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="So You&#8217;re Anti-Glasses?: Dismantling Right Wing Arguments" align="center" style="display: block;margin: 0 auto 20px;max-width:100%;" /></a><div class="e-content">
<p>Sometimes it’s difficult to see inequality. Particularly when it’s the structural kind.  (Previously discussed in <a href="https://ideatrash.net/2015/08/you-might-be-acting-like-bigot-and.html">You might be acting like a bigot – and never mean to</a>, <a href="https://ideatrash.net/2017/08/the-cowardly-way-to-address-racism-and.html">The Cowardly Way To Address Racism (and other bigotry)</a>, and <a href="https://ideatrash.net/2009/11/structures-of-power-vignette-six.html">Structures of Power (Vignette Six)</a>. </p>



<p>In the hopes of closing <a href="https://ideatrash.net/2019/09/illustrating-the-empathy-gap-with-music.html">the empathy gap just a little bit</a>, I’d like to offer a simple analogy / argument that might help when it comes to that awkward after-dinner conversation.</p>



<p>When it comes to education (including affirmative action and the rest), right-wingers like to go on about “equality” and “merit”. And there’s something to both of those – but they’re missing (or ignoring) the pretty obvious counter-example:  Not all education environments or education needs are equal.</p>



<p>Let’s say you’ve got two schools with equally talented students and teachers.  One school has air-conditioning, computers, and the latest textbooks. The other school has none of those things. Which set of students do you think is going to do better?</p>



<p>And then, when the right-winger says something about individual students excelling regardless (because they <em>will</em>), ask this simple question: “Which of those schools would you want <em>your</em> child to go to?”</p>



<p>Then, if they continue to go on about “merit”, ask them if they’re in favor of banning glasses and contacts. </p>



<p>If you take their argument about “individual merit” to its logical endpoint, every student does not get assistance with their vision, so why should <em>any</em>? Therefore, they must believe that any student with glasses is getting an “unfair advantage”.</p>



<p>Be sure to use this one if they wear glasses themselves.</p>



<p>Featured Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@ugodly?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Ugo °</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/glasses?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Unsplash</a></p>
</div><img src="https://stevensaus.com/matomo/piwik.php?idsite=2&amp;rec=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2F2019%2F11%2Fso-youre-anti-glasses-dismantling-right-wing-arguments.html%3Fpk_campaign%3Dfeed%26pk_kwd%3Dso-youre-anti-glasses-dismantling-right-wing-arguments&amp;action_name=%3Cspan+class%3D%27p-name%27%3ESo+You%26%238217%3Bre+Anti-Glasses%3F%3A+Dismantling+Right+Wing+Arguments%3C%2Fspan%3E&amp;urlref=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2Ffeed" width="0" alt="" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;">]]></content:encoded>
									<enclosure url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ugo-4EDJgGj419U-unsplash.jpg" length="73617" type="image/jpeg"/><media:content url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ugo-4EDJgGj419U-unsplash.jpg" width="1200" height="800" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">103458</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prosperity Theology: Things To NOT Be Thankful For</title>
		<link>https://ideatrash.net/2019/11/prosperity-theology-things-to-not-be-thankful-for.html?pk_campaign=feed&#038;pk_kwd=prosperity-theology-things-to-not-be-thankful-for</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 01:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[<span class='p-author h-card'>steven</span>]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faith]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ideatrash.net/?p=103447</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Prosperity theology is entirely made up of dupes and the greedy who prey upon them.  BAR NONE.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://ideatrash.net/2019/11/prosperity-theology-things-to-not-be-thankful-for.html?pk_campaign=feed&pk_kwd=prosperity-theology-things-to-not-be-thankful-for"><img width="300" height="199" src="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/stephen-radford-86QxYjwq8LU-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="Prosperity Theology: Things To NOT Be Thankful For" align="center" style="display: block;margin: 0 auto 20px;max-width:100%;" /></a><div class="e-content">
<p>As we head into Thanksgiving (for USAians), lots of people are focusing on things to be thankful for. There’s nothing wrong with that – not at all!  But there’s also a <em>lot</em> of crap that we <em>shouldn’t</em> be thankful for.</p>



<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prosperity_theology" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Prosperity Theology</a> (aka “health and wealth theology”) is one of them.</p>



<p>Advocates of this doctrine – sometimes called the “Prosperity Gospel” – is <em>entirely</em> made up of dupes and the greedy who prey upon them.  <strong>BAR NONE</strong>.</p>



<p>The quick version of this bullshirt preaching is simple:  The more faithful you are (and the more you give to preachers who spout this carp), the better off you are physically, mentally, and financially. To quote Wikipedia:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Prosperity theology views the Bible as a contract between God and humans: if humans have faith in God, he will deliver security and prosperity.</p><cite>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prosperity_theology</cite></blockquote>



<p>This idea is <em>forking evil</em>.  <strong>I cannot stress this enough</strong>. It is blaming the victim writ large.  Bad things happening to you? This worldview claims it’s <em>your</em> fault – you’re not faithful enough, you’re not praying hard enough, and you’re <em>definitely</em> not giving enough money to those preaching the prosperity gospel.</p>



<p>How <em>horrific</em> an idea is that?  It’s the ultimate predatory scam: if results don’t match expectations, it’s still the fault of the sick, poor, and disadvantaged.  This kind of thinking destroys people and destroys faith.</p>



<p>And yet it’s a major movement, with some of the major movers and shakers including names you’ve probably heard of, including Oral Roberts, the Swaggarts, T. D. Jakes, Guillermo Maldonado, Joel Osteen, and Paula White.</p>



<p>What’s worse, is that it <em>doesn’t even mesh with the Bible</em>.  Like, at all.  </p>



<p>Aside from the Gospels and Acts (y’know, where the Son of God and His most faithful get <em>killed</em> for believing), <a href="https://www.sparknotes.com/lit/oldtestament/section11/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">there’s the <em>entire</em> book of Job</a>.</p>



<p>If you’re unfamiliar, this book in the Old Testament outlines a bet between God and Satan that a prosperous and faithful man (Job) will renounce his faith in God if he loses everything.  God agrees to the bet, then begins to systematically destroy Job’s wealth and <em>slaughters Job’s family</em> until Job is left penniless.  Job’s “friends” sound like prosperity preachers themselves.  Instead of rallying around their friend, they insinuate that Job <em>must</em> have been sinful to deserve such punishment.  </p>



<p>Except that’s not the case.  Job remains faithful throughout, eventually having a new family and new wealth granted to him by God after the bet is over [1].</p>



<p>This <em>entire book</em> of the Bible is <em>expressly</em> a rebuttal of prosperity theology.  There is <em>no way</em> that someone claiming to be a Christian preacher would be unaware of this book in the Bible and the message it contains.  Yet they still preach the opposite, not caring that it goes against the very faith they claim to spread.</p>



<p>And that’s why I say that <em><strong>everyone</strong></em> involved with prosperity theology is either duped or an evil greedy fartwaffle <em>deliberately</em> preying upon others.</p>



<p>Prosperity theology, you are something that <em>no-one</em> should be grateful for. </p>



<p>Where’s the Inquisition when you need them?</p>



<p>Featured Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@steve228uk?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Stephen Radford</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/preacher?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>(PS – I love that the featured photo has the book of Ecclesiastes showing.  “Vanity of vanities, saith the Preacher, vanity of vanities; all is vanity. What profit hath a man of all his labour which he taketh under the sun?”)</p>



<p>[1] There’s issues with the way that God “answers” Job’s questions about why this happened to him – and it paints God as a bit of a dick.  I mean, if nothing else, “Hey, I killed your old wife and kids, so here’s a new wife and kids,” (Job 42:12-17) is <em>amazingly</em> clueless.</p>
</div><img src="https://stevensaus.com/matomo/piwik.php?idsite=2&amp;rec=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2F2019%2F11%2Fprosperity-theology-things-to-not-be-thankful-for.html%3Fpk_campaign%3Dfeed%26pk_kwd%3Dprosperity-theology-things-to-not-be-thankful-for&amp;action_name=%3Cspan+class%3D%27p-name%27%3EProsperity+Theology%3A+Things+To+NOT+Be+Thankful+For%3C%2Fspan%3E&amp;urlref=https%3A%2F%2Fideatrash.net%2Ffeed" width="0" alt="" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;">]]></content:encoded>
									<enclosure url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/stephen-radford-86QxYjwq8LU-unsplash.jpg" length="74876" type="image/jpeg"/><media:content url="https://ideatrash.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/stephen-radford-86QxYjwq8LU-unsplash.jpg" width="1200" height="797" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/><post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">103447</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
